A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Economic Development Administration, Program Files of William P. Gormbley FA529
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Economic Development Administration, Program Files of William P. Gormbley
1953-1968
Rockefeller Archive Center
Gormbley, William P.
Ford Foundation
FA529
2.62 Cubic Feet 2 standard record storage boxes.
Conditions Governing Access note
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains grant appropriation summaries, program and project reports, and abstracts.
Biographical / Historical
William P. Gormbley, Jr. began his career at the Ford Foundation as a program associate within the Ford Foundation's Economic Development and Administration program in 1962. By 1964, he was the associate director of the Economic Development and Administration. In 1965, after some restructuring at the Foundation, Gormbley served assistant to the vice president of the Division of Administration program. In 1970, he was the officer in charge of the Manpower Services program (which became Personnel Services and later the Office of Personnel and Administrative Services) within the Admininistration Division. Gormbley left the Foundation in 1982.
Arrangement
As received.
- Grants Appropriation Summaries (1/2), 1953 October (Box 1)
- Grants Appropriation Summaries (2/2), 1953 October (Box 1)
- Grant and Appropriations Summaries -- Table of Contents and Aphabetical Index, 1953 October (Box 1)
- Grant and Appropriations Summaries -- Vol. 1 -- International A-H, 1953 October (Box 1)
- Grant and Appropriations Summaries -- Vol. 2 -- International I and J, 1953 October (Box 1)
- Grant and Appropriations Summaries -- Vol. 3 -- International K and L, 1953 October (Box 1)
- Grant and Appropriations Summaries -- Vol. 4 -- Free Institutions -- Economic Well-Being -- Education -- Behavioral Sciences -- Michigan Committee Projects, 1953 October (Box 1)
- Grant Summaries -- EDA Budget, 1957 (Box 1)
- EDA Business Conferences, 1957-1961 (Box 1)
- Committee for Economic Development, 1964 (Box 1)
- Corporate Management Development Program -- General Electric, 1963 (Box 1)
- Corporate Management Development Program -- IBM (Box 1)
- GCT -- Terminal Aid to Business Education, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
- General Electric Co. -- Meetings on Educational Relations Activities (between Industries and Foundations), 1963 (Box 1)
- International Marketing Institute (James Hagler), 1963-1965 (Box 1)
- Projects -- Mathematics in Business School Curriculum, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
- Projects -- Programmed Learning for Business (University of Michigan -- Odiorne) (Box 1)
- Abstracts Projects, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 1968 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 67-400--67-602, 1967 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 67-200--67-399, 1967 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 67-1--67-199, 1967 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 66-267--66-423, 1966 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 66-1--66-266, 1966 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 64-303--1965, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 1963-64-301, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
- Abstracts Deleted, 1965 (Box 2)